okay uh
I'm gonna start three paragraphs before
where it says stopped here
it says
so
uh just a bag of
oatmeal on your belt comes from the
effort of countless people uh
and the place that you're staying in
somebody somebody told me they were in a
tent this morning
Joe and uh but still the tent was made
by somebody right
and uh
and then uh even your own clothing like
like for a monk or none it would be your
shawl something you're always wearing
we gave a different example for you guys
okay
uh
and we're ready to start again these are
reasons why
other people have an investment in your
time
and you have an obligation to them
because you are already by living
you are using up other people's time
okay by eating by by wearing clothes by
staying in a building by driving on a
road
you are using up other people's time so
they have some right
just technically they have some rights
to your body
into your time okay
okay already they have rights to you
okay and we're gonna start we're gonna
continue on that idea and the next one
is kind of awesome okay the whole thing
is awesome but okay
uh uh so right now you have uh the 18
leisures and fortunes
and there's a nice summary of them in a
new book by
so gang
uh that's coming out shortly
uh or lonely uh and uh no the ending of
those books is a lot of work it's
hundreds of hours of work so
close
but the fact that you have a human body
uh the fact that you're alive
the fact that you
have time to come to Diamond Mountain if
you're not here you're a loser
okay uh but that's just my opinion
[Music]
so uh
I mean it's the greatest Retreat Center
in the world I I can say that without
exaggeration I I exaggerate a little bit
but uh
it really is as far as I know
okay um
so the fact that you have a body
uh the fact that you're alive
is because
you did good things to other people in
the past okay
the reason you have eyes and ears to
listen to this teaching
the reason that you're still alive
body's still working
uh
it's because of
good things you did to other people you
you are proof
of millions of Good Deeds
so actually you owe them
because of your body
and because of your eyes
because of
that you're alive and you're breathing
okay you owe other people because if
they hadn't been there for you to be
nice to you wouldn't be here got it so
now there's a new Dent now this one's
the worst one
you know the fact that you're alive and
you're breathing and you're here
is is proof that you did countless good
things to other people
and if there were not we're not other
people
then you wouldn't be here got it
you you'd just be
floating between planets which is a drug
I've been there
so have you
uh so
you owe them for that reason your
clothes
your house
and your body and your mind and your
eyes and your ears you owe to other
people okay so they have some claim
to your to those things
and it's it's not uh exaggerated
they have a valid claim
to some of your attention because they
gave you ice and ears and
years okay
you owe them Todd took chanchu to some
kitchen
in fact for you to study this subject
right now
which is basically how to reach love for
the whole universe and serve them
directly
each person directly
that attempt or that that occupation
that you're in right now this week
you can't do it without them
so you owe them for that
you want to be a police officer yeah
well they're nice to other people
okay
so you can't be a buddhistoper without
them right
so you owe them already you just want to
become a buddhisattva you're already in
debt
because you can't be a buddy stuff and
without somebody to be a buddy sign for
four
okay so you owe them again
it's getting radical you you're done to
them it's worse than MasterCard okay
um
even for you to become a Buddha
which you will depend on other people so
you owe them in advance also that's like
my credit card okay they start charging
me interest in
the fact that you have someone to have
compassion towards
Sam k.u the fact that you have someone
to want to get enlightened for
and then he starts going through the six
Perfections and that's really heavy
who's gonna give me the first one for
ten dollars because this is easy
dude
now wait the exercise here is we're
gonna have how many imperfections
six roughly
and we want to know why they depend on
other people like I can't get the first
one without
other people because
because to be able to give which is
yeah I need to be able to give gifts
yeah you can't be about yourself
you can't be a body sniper if you don't
do the six Perfections you can't do the
first of the six Perfections if there's
nobody to give stuff to so you owe them
again okay
all right we're getting that's the hard
one now here comes the easy one
oh she's checking the six professors
go ahead what's the second one
yeah and uh you know they say uh vinaya
or or morality or it's so trim or you
know there's many many words for it uh
uh but in the end uh morality boils down
to being nice to other people
I I don't like the word morality too
much it's it's a kind of a weird word
ethics is too technical
but being nice to other people it's a
nice definition of morality
so you can't do that without
other people to be nice too all right
who's got the third one
no that's selfish handing around
third one
third perfection
yeah yes but why is it relevant here
yeah without
we have so we are so lucky to have a
good supply of annoying annoying people
uh otherwise we couldn't do the third
perfection
so you owe them
four
effort
and why does it require other people
why do you need other people for number
four
fundraising
to bring the people of happiness say
again
because we need to bring people
happiness yeah and you have to work hard
you could yeah
you need other people to work for
otherwise you know there's no way to
work for it you don't have to do the
fourth perfection
it's work hard
but what's the definition of the fourth
profession
yeah yeah having fun doing having fun
helping other people so uh
whether other people are nice or whether
people are annoying
you need them to have fun with
it's easy to have fun with nice people
but real bodhisattvas enjoy having fun
with irritating people okay
okay now just imagine it's easy to have
fun with nice people
but if you can reach this point in your
practice
where you can have fun with really
irritating people like
being inspectors who will come to your
Cafe for four years and always find one
more thing
if you can have fun with them
then you can have fun all the time
you see I mean so you need other people
to have fun with that's the fourth
that's the real fourth Perfection if you
can have fun
with people who are not fun
then you really have fun
okay fifth one who's got the fifth one
but
um
I I but why does it depend a lot of
people
I'm guessing because you test yourself
good good answer you test yourself
people are so irritating
and people interrupt you
all day
when you're trying to focus or do your
meditation or do do other things when
you're trying to focus
it seems to be
the harder you try the more people come
to interrupt you
okay it's a special Buddhist practice
to interrupt people so uh
so you can't develop focus without
interruptions
so all the garbage truck drivers
in
Geneva where you guys live
Lutheran sorry
all the garbage truck drivers should get
an award from all the Buddhist
meditators
for helping you develop your your focus
right
the garbage trucks in New York
because it was a good way if you can
take to a garbage truck visit you can
meditate anywhere okay sixth one
[Music]
it was a wisdom
we need the people at least at the level
of knowledge understanding that the
absence of anybody not coming from me
nice nice good
uh so there's two kinds of emptiness The
Emptiness of people and things
The Emptiness of
people is very necessary to see
emptiness you have to understand the
emptiness of the people around you
they need that you need people
to think about their emptiness what is
their emptiness
when said it very nicely uh
they're coming
there's nobody in your life
who's not coming from you
who's not coming from you when people
are nice to you you don't think so much
about where they're coming from
but when people are bad to you you think
about why me
and what did I do you know so especially
if irritating people are excellent
objects to meditate on emptiness you
know you want to reach a gokja you want
to reach the thing that's not there
it's an irritating person who is not
coming from me
okay and that's that's you don't need
more emptiness than that
okay you never met a person
who wasn't coming from you
if there wasn't other people around you
could never remember that okay so seeing
emptiness depends on other people okay
so you owe them
thank you for being empty
you know thank you for irritating me so
I could
remember that you're coming from me
can't do any of this
these Perfections without other people
you want to go deeper yeah
it's really irritating for Mr leonhardt
because
then I never I never get enough done
in the retreat but I don't care uh
[Music]
there's ten Perfections
that's good
to the last four
she
four ways of collecting disciples
give me any of them I don't
know yeah the first one is generosity
the first one is uh
so why does that depend on other people
Daniel
because you need other people to be
generous towards you you need students
right the other people if you're a
teacher then who are you going to teach
if there's no other people yeah you
cannot do the seventh perfection
uh without someone to feed or give money
to
or
give what do you call that Tim free
rides at Diamond Mountain
you need you need students you need
needy students
okay or you can't do this seventh
profession what's the a tour what's that
second
whoa are you sure this is a good idea
um the eight is uh try to have your
student practice what you teach
yeah that's at least that's one of them
yeah uh trying to get them trying to
help your students to practice what you
preach okay don't let them become
somebody told me
wow guess what I'm gonna teach a class
at The Retreat you know and I said
they said do you have any advice and I
said well
you are rising to a new level of
hypocrisy
because you get to look people in the
face and tell them to be honest and good
and
when you're not
yourself you see what I mean so uh yeah
if there weren't other people around
to be a good example for you you
wouldn't have any reason to be
if you were alone in the world you could
steal and lie and cheat and
it wouldn't matter
okay
got I got two more here
praising them lavishly
yeah praise them obviously when they do
something right okay
obviously you couldn't do that if you
didn't
have other people around
okay what's the last one
um
yeah never mind
that is an important one is there's like
being Fierce being being tough when you
need to
no no not she get one done that's the
four months
um as I remember the last ones is
do what you teach yeah the most
difficult one do what you teach
yeah
Do What You Preach right
huh
isn't that the same as good examples
yeah maybe you got another one Tim
ing
teach according the capacity of the
student is it
McDonald's
cat
have fun with them
nobody
I think it's uh finding a good place
to have the teachings
I'm gonna look it up if you don't get it
maybe it's a rejoicing this is getting
too slow that's what I think
to see them disappear from your
perception
that's the Ultimate Dream okay
it's called doing let's let's ask John
Brady
what is it
according to Google
I don't trust Google
it should be pleasant teach according to
the person's needs and act in accordance
with what you teach
so she gets to 50
[Laughter]
.
which means
help them out physically
and financially
praised them obviously when they do
something right which
doesn't require much time
uh
then Timber
Act in accordance
I
and then chipper
means do the thing I don't know
so to do the thing is to do what you
teach
and do what you teach he's number four
right and number three is teach to the
capacity the student
s okay and that sounds okay all right
[Music]
um
oh yeah okay here it says
yeah
not only to their capacity but also to
their wishes
so there's a slight difference there
okay
all right uh then he quotes uh
he says to do the Perfections you need
other people
and he quotes
and he says
U
Jawa means
since you need other people
to get enlightened as much as you need
Buddhas to teach you how to get
enlightened okay
since you need other people to get
enlightened with to
to practice of Perfections since you
need other people and since you need
Buddhas also to teach you to get
enlightened
ation do
why why do you weird guys respect the
Buddhists
but not other people
he says it's not logical okay if if you
need other people to get enlightened
as much as you need Buddhas to teach you
how to get enlightened
and if you accept that you should
respect Buddhists because they teach you
how to get enlightened then why don't
you respect other people equally
okay cool that's Shanty doing check
check means half
it's a beautiful word here so Che means
uh half of what you need to get
enlightened comes from the Buddhas but
half of what you need comes from the
kindness of other people who irritate
you who take your money
stuff like that okay good
who needs you okay okay so why it's
illogical that you don't respect all
these other people the way you respect
your teacher
I got respect recently I was at
um I was on a flight to uh Vietnam and
Japan
and uh
have this status with United Airlines
which is called what's it called
Global Services
it it it's not on the website you need
it's a vote by the board of directors of
United Airlines it's a secret category
and you get you know you get this this
they vote and they and they they tell
you you're now your Global Services and
they prostrate to you at the ticket
counter and everything and I'm like God
now I know what it feels like to be a
llama because uh when I go on these long
flights and they come to my seat and
they thank me
and and they say do you need anything
and I'm like wow yeah
okay I'm not complaining I'm
I get pampered a lot
um
then he's gonna quote uh look if you
need other people so much to get
enlightened then actually they are your
ticket to heaven right we call it ticket
to heaven what's the low Zhong
expression
wish giving gym nice gentle money okay
um
and we have a picture here
all right
kind of corny
yeah
uh this is not the diamond and the rose
thing this just means that's my
that's the closest picture I could find
to a wish giving gem okay
okay and the low jump the uh
the ancient books from about a thousand
years ago the kandampas
say
uh there is a special Jewel you find it
under the
ground or something
and then you have to
as I mentioned sorry
you have to
put it up on a flagpole you have to do
certain prayers to it and then it will
give you sorry anything you
uh all right I think I'm allergic to
lojo okay
um
[Music]
so other people are like a wish-giving
gem if you have other people around you
can reach your goals if you don't have
other people around you cannot reach
your goals
and I think if you've done a three-year
Retreat those of us who have done a
three year two I know Kat if you had
this experience but uh
you start to miss other people
uh to do things for
and it's kind of weird it's kind of
weird to spend three years meditating
and and
you know and there's nobody around
physically to
to do nice things for and you kind of
get hungry
to get out of retreat and do things for
people okay so I think when you do a
retreat you sort of become very
sensitive to the the
how lucky you are when you have other
people around to help to do things for
because that's what really makes people
happy
that's what makes people happy
Shin Tian was telling me uh
I was bragging about my grandkid who I'm
gonna see on my day off in Tucson and
she said oh yeah all my relatives when
they had kids they were all working they
sent the kids to me
to babysit I don't know like three
families four families kids
and she was saying how fun it was and
how she treasured it
and how she misses it now they grew up
so uh
it's like that you need other people
they are like a wishing jump okay now
you should jump up and down and
celebrate no I'm kidding uh we reached
uh another day what does that mean
s
time to meditate no no
another day in the teachings of pobanka
rinpoche yeah so this is a 24-day
teaching
and uh and we we reach a new
day like once a year or something and so
I'd like to announce you have reached a
new date
ah okay
so I am making progress Tim uh day 18
okay uh out of 24 days but we have
covered 21 and 22 I think it is already
so actually we're getting close
okay and uh just to remember
this lamrim was an oral teaching for 24
days
um to I don't know a thousand or two
thousand people Veronica asked me
how did they teach that many people we
were watching
um
The Chosen which is a beautiful TV
series about the life of Jesus
and um it's a crowdfunding and the 100
million people have seen it no and it's
a beautiful uh series on Netflix no now
it's do you just look it up the Chosen
and it's free and and it's a beautiful
uh series about the life of Jesus and by
the way today's Easter
and those of you who are Christian uh
congratulations
uh and happy Easter I hope you get
chocolate eggs I didn't but um
so anyway uh
that we were watching The Sermon on the
Mount which is you know
what's cool about that TV series we
should do some work then
it's kind of lame that we didn't think
of it first uh but uh they have uh if
you crowdfund you get to be in the in
the series
see what I mean so
people who give five dollars to the
crowd funding get to be at The Sermon on
the Mount and they dress you up like a
you know a Palestinian
and you get to be uh in the audience and
I think it's really fun it's really cool
so Veronica asked me we were watching it
and
she said um
what how did how did those Buddhist
teachers talk to a thousand people or
two thousand people and I said they were
loud
and there was no microphones and they
would find natural amphitheaters and if
you've ever been to one they're very
beautiful
and if you speak loudly you can speak to
a couple thousand people
and people will hear you know and then
there's this other thing where people
tell the people behind them what they
said
so uh
we're in and my teacher was at uh those
teachings not this series but a later
series uh Cameron Bache was there
gave those teachings and there's a
famous scene which I've told you before
my teacher was a goofball not serious
student enjoyed
putting some tax on the past where the
monks would walk barefoot and that was
his total
connection to the monastery and uh
and then he got stuck with working in
the kitchen
uh and uh came into the kitchen and and
and touched his hand
and he says this one looks good this one
looks smart you know and then he just
went away and uh and something happened
to my teacher
and he became the greatest gache of his
time
he beat 15 000 people in the debates
so it's kind of a cool
story means there's hope for us too
all right okay
uh so 18th day
uh so at the beginning about when the oh
and by the way I think you should say
that there was a young
reincarnated llama in the audience named
and uh he took notes he took very
careful notes
and uh
and then he he showed the notes to
public the
beaker
and Papa said wow your notes are awesome
can you can you do the whole teaching so
he took notes for 18 days
and then he wrote them up uh
and it's the it took him about 10 years
to finish the manuscript and that's why
we have the aluminum
and uh
he became the teacher of the Dilemma
so and he was my teacher's teacher
so that's teacher
teacher and it is the greatest book ever
written in into
Greenlee
ful like
uh and funny at many places which is
also beautiful okay
okay checking out with some kind of
Chambers soon
uh then he quotes uh
so when you start off a new day he'll
give him a pep talk why
people are not settled down yet
you have a thousand people coming in
are Milling around people talking people
focused yet
so it's tradition to quote quote
something and get people settled down so
he quotes sonkappa
and he quotes this line
which means
people are Swept Away by four Fierce
river currents
and then he
here's a picture
[Music]
okay that's us but it's worse than that
okay
so uh when he quotes a single line
he's cloning a verse and I like to go
get the verse for you and teach you the
whole verse
it slows things down and I don't care
okay uh
so here's the whole verse
and I taught it in uh Mongolia
uh I I went to Mongolia just after they
got their independence back and
and I within six months after they got
their independence back
and they were going wild about Buddhism
at the time
and they put me in a
Stadium
it's the where the the stadium where the
Mongolian circus uses
which is their football team and uh
and I taught with bakala rimpachi who's
a great great
uh doci
geshe and a prince of ladakh
and a member of the Indian Congress
and the ambassador to Mongolia
so we taught together he was very old at
the time
people were bringing
people paralyzed people on stretchers
and pushing them onto the stage
to see if we could heal them during the
teaching I'm like Barclay everyone
saying that's your thing
but he was very old at the time and
there was a problem in Mongolia people
drinking too much drinking in
he would go out at night on the street
and and
find drunk people and yell at them and
take away their alcohol and he's like
80.
and uh so it was a wonderful teaching so
we taught this verse I remember this
verse we taught this verse in
uh it was very beautiful
people are carried away on four Great
Rivers
and you can explain that two different
ways the the
I think the best one is
for a hundred dollars
first
aging sickness dying yeah
birth aging sickness and death okay
okay so people are Swept Away by these
Rivers they don't have a choice
and everybody's drowning
okay everybody in this room
everybody in this world on this planet
is drowning okay everybody
is drowning you didn't ask to come here
uh you don't have a choice about getting
older
you get sick from time to time
and it and in the end you have to die
and you have no choice at all you are
you are in a huge Mighty River and
you're being carried off and you don't
have any choice
and uh so people are sheepdog
so that's okay
that's not too bad
but you are handcuffed
by your camera
you have limitations on how much you can
study uh how much uh scriptures you can
read how many teachers you can meet you
you are you have handcuffed by
limitations you're thrown into a huge
Mighty River and you are Hancock
by your commas you can't swim I guess
you have to kick hard
right and
damn dungeon chocolate
boosted sir just after they handcuffed
you and before they threw you in the
river they stuck you in an iron cage and
threw that in the river
okay this they stuck you in an iron cage
and threw that in the river what's that
dongs in
you
even as the pen is explained even as you
explain the pen
you believe it's not coming from you
irony of
even while you're teaching the pen to
people
you believe it came from a factory
even as you hold a pan up
you believe it came from a factory okay
Okay so
you couldn't get out anyway
you know suppose you could swim hard or
someone threw you were a rope or
something
couldn't you're handcuffed by your past
Karma you're uh
I hate to say fate but I have Chinese
friends it seems in Chinese culture fate
is a big thing and Chinese friends are
always asking me can I break my faith
and you can but it's extremely difficult
okay most of your life was preordained
at Birth by the what you did before you
came here you're on a certain
path
created by your path past Karma
that's even that's enough to drown you
but before they put their handcuffs on
after they put the handcuffs on they
threw you in an iron Cajun into your
land in the river
and that's that you tend to
repeat the same mistakes because and
that's where the why the Wheel of Life
is a wheel
[Music]
and you tend to repeat the same mistakes
because you firmly believe that things
are not coming from
and that's like hopeless
Four Rivers Hancock
jammed into an iron cage thrown into the
river okay
and it is night time
they can't see anything
it's the dead of night
okay and that's again uh mareka
which sugan can tell you is it's a
personal ignorance about your own self
and your own condition
I
forget parents you don't even understand
yourself
and that causes all your suffering
you you are a result of your Justice
and you are coming from you from you and
your thoughts are flowing from your
seeds and you're just listening you're
not thinking
you're just watching thoughts open from
past seeds if if you don't even have the
freedom to sing how are you gonna get up
you're
it's dark you're smothered in darkness
and you have been in this condition for
countless lifetimes
it's not a new thing
it's like birth number billion 10
billion zillion zillion okay
uh you are tortured by the three kinds
of suffering without a break
while you're here what are they
fifty dollars
[Music]
the first one is uh suffering of change
everything is changing going up and down
okay that's the second one the second
one what's the class oh uh like the
first one is the suffering of suffering
or something like that like a broken leg
or a heart or the number one outright
pain you know you gotta anticipate
someone
you know your back hurts something like
that you
you have a bad day with your wife or
husband okay that's one number two
change
the way I the way they stare at the
scripture is a nice French dinner
okay
third one
is the inheritance and the fact is you
have to die and yeah just your overall
lousy conditions
okay the the fact that
you have to get old and die
50 bucks
okay
collect from dig me if you don't collect
it's not my problem
okay
by thinking about how everyone else is
in this condition that's all that's the
verse
he started the teaching with that verse
okay
all right
[Music]
all right Mike Mundo
there you go
London
for a hundred dollars
and this is not sure that's Dharma
there's an apostrophe in front of it
there's a different spelling
cancel the bed
huh
if the microphone fails you don't get
the money
[Laughter]
it's your bad motivation right say again
like bad motivations
no no uh oh say again bad motivation no
it's the opposite good motivation
[Laughter]
yeah Champa here means to fix your it
means to
in English we say raise your motivation
before class
like they they don't like to start a
class
in the ancient times
without thinking about why you're in the
class that's all
so you're not supposed to start a class
before you think about why you came to
the class okay
that's called
it's a pep talk
it's a Dharma peptide okay
then he went over the
outline that he that he's in and that's
a Buddhist tradition
you know put put the teaching in the
flow I'll give two hundred dollars for
the Five Points of our outline
[Music]
how much money did you say 200.
um everyone has an equal right to 6
6 equal rights to happiness number right
to happiness
uh the problems of self-charging yeah
the advantages of taking care of others
through exchanging self and other
yeah tongling
you
do
I tell you 100 has to go to Ben
okay thank you Mom for dinner okay
tell them I miss him I mean uh
good
Sam Jones
He reviewed the seven steps to
what do you call it getting borutina
according to whose system
true
is it a teacher I'm not sure but if you
can give me the seven I'll give you a
hundred dollars
and I put him up here
I gotta check my bank account right
it's a gun
he's gonna read the Tibetan the first
one is to think of
um everybody as your mother
understand they have been I understand
that yeah okay and then second is to
understand that they have been very kind
to us yeah remember their kindness and
then number three is to uh
that thing that we want to repay the
kindness nice we pay the kindness number
three and number four is to have the
love to them give them nice things yes
and then number five is to take away
their suffering compassion
number six is to to do it no matter what
personal responsibility and number seven
is the body cheetah yeah
[Applause]
so you have to collect from Tim no I'm
kidding
me okay
what time Tim what time we have to stop
yeah let's do a little meditation okay
all right
we'll just do about 10 minutes and we'll
do another meditation in the second hour
today uh
but I
at least once this week I would like to
take you through how to start a
meditation and I know you did it a
hundred times
but I want to make sure everyone's doing
it okay
so just once this week
uh we'll do a proper
preparation for a meditation a mental
preparation okay
and uh
yes for almost 50 years
and it's I still enjoyed doing I it's
very beautiful and I I don't meditate
without doing this
uh so I'll do it every day when I
meditate I do this every
and um
I think it's I think it's a beautiful
way to it's beautiful to do it once a
day
okay so uh I I spend
a lot of time to get ready for a
meditation mentally
and it takes about I don't know
10 15 minutes just to go into a
meditation okay so I strongly advise you
to do it and get used to it and you
don't have to do it every day if you're
on a short schedule if you're the
treasurer of some major city in Colorado
you can
shorten it or go straight to your
meditation okay okay but uh
a couple times a week
do a nice preparation
[Music]
after almost 50 years of meditating I
actually it is more than 50 years
um
I still think it's good to start with a
breathing practice
and
10 breaths just doesn't do it for me I
need a hundred breaths it's about five
minutes
so
we're gonna do a hundred breaths you're
gonna
lose count three or four times that's
okay come back
focus on the exhale first and then on
the inhale
foreign
then we'll go through the seven
steps to preparation
the first step is supposed to be
prostration personally
I like to choose
someone
that I've been around in the last week
or so who is an inspiration to me and I
do a mental
prostration and oftentimes they are not
a Buddhist they're just
someone who is
acting in a very
good way
and who inspires me and somebody I I
would like to be like them
so I do a mental prostration
by thinking of someone
who is inspiring to me and it's not
necessarily a famous person or something
oftentimes it's
just someone I met
doing something beautiful for other
people
the next one is prostration
or offering
so I'd like to
imagine that I'm offering them
something and I I always come back
personally to
offering them something good I did in
the last week or so
I make a small offering
of something
and I did good in the last few days
the third step here is uh confession or
admitting some mistake I made in the
last week or so
trying to think of some
mistake you've made
and be honest about it it helps a lot to
purify a Karma to
sorry
it made a mistake that we made
in the last week or so
eventually it helps a lot to tell
somebody else
it's good to do it in your meditation
but it's nice to have some friends that
you can
share your mistakes with then you can
really improve quickly
and then share
something good you did with this person
in the last week
people have a natural tendency to
focus on their mistakes and we all
have
some trouble to admit when we're doing
something right
without Pride
so don't be
afraid to
admit that you're doing a lot of good
things
and just choose one
good thing and without Pride
rejoice and be happy
in the next step is to ask for teachings
and number five
and
for me uh
teachings might come in two different
ways one is uh
oftentimes when I'm
looking at the great books
the Great
Buddhist books
I see I see beautiful teachings for my
day I see things that are going to help
me
today
and then oftentimes
I'll get teachings from other people
either somebody will say something sweet
and I'll get a teaching from it or
someone will challenge me
someone will cause me some trouble
and then I will
take a teaching from that so
ask ask for those teachings
pray
that you get positive teachings and
teachings too difficult
difficult things and difficult people
and number six uh ask your teachers to
stay
I have a lot of teachers who come to me
in in the world
to me through the
music also have some very
my dearest teachers are still alive
and ask them to stay in your life
foreign
normally we would start our meditation
whatever is our
meditation that we're working on
and then after that we would dedicate
the Great Karma I like to
think of a specific people I know who
are having a hard time
maybe they are sick or
or maybe
they're having a hard time personally
in their family life or something and
then I will
send the Good Karma of the meditation to
them
so let's dedicate the karma
and then slowly open your eyes
take a stretch
drink something if you're in Arizona you
have to drink
foreign
[Music]
goes through the brain the blood is
mostly water
if you don't drink you get stupid
seriously
uh we're gonna stop there and Tim and
then uh I'll take questions and we'll
come back in half an hour okay
and I'll take questions at the beginning
of the next class okay so 15 minutes of
questions
and uh
have a break
stretch
go to the emergency room
I've seen half an hour right Tim
oh one last thing
Senor Ultima Costa
uh
you have an image sugan of uh
Diamond Cutter press
uh is offering uh some books for free
which is a good deal
so there's three books uh today that
that Rosa and jigmay would like to and
Katie would like to offer everybody
and uh
here's the the one in the middle is the
art of sharing this is the translation
of the story of King
SRI Cena
we translated it it's done Anatole
helped me check the English and it's a
beautiful story
from the long room
and Diamond Cutter press is working to
publish
ebooks of the ACI courses
give them away for free yeah
so that's uh a lot of work Rosa and
jigmaid did a lot of work and they're
gonna try to do all the courses
and so the first two courses are done
and I did not have time and I will not
have time to
to check them for a small
corrections but they're about 99 percent
clean
so
they'll be publishing all the 18
Foundation courses
and then I'm sure they'll go on to the
18 Diamond way courses in time for
any possible Diamond way TTS okay
say again
yeah
okay take a break
get your free book during the break